Finding Aid for the Alexis Kall Papers LSC.0601
UCLA Library Special Collections
Alexis Kall papers
1917-1940
UCLA Library Special Collections
Kall, Alexis
LSC.0601
2.5 Linear Feet (5 boxes)
Alexis Kall (b.1878) taught at the Imperial University in St. Petersburg, Russia. The collection consists of Kall's correspondence, papers, notebooks, and memorabilia. There is also a typescript manuscript on Stravinsky by Kall.
Conditions Governing Access
Portions of collection unprocessed. Some material in the collection are unavailable for access. Please contact Special Collections reference (spec-coll@library.ucla.edu) for more information.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Jay Leyda and Dr. Sergei Bertensson.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942332353606533
Biography
Kall taught at the Imperial University in St. Petersburg, Russia; he was a friend and one-time secretary of Igor Stravinsky.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of correspondence, papers, notebooks, and memorabilia of Dr. Alexis Kall. Includes typescript manuscript on Stravinsky by Kall.
Manuscripts for publication; Musicologists -- Russia -- St. Petersburg -- Archives.; College teachers -- Russia -- St. Petersburg -- Archives.; Kall, Alexis, 1878- --Archives.
- Correspondence, English, c.1930-1950 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, Dagmar Godowsky, c.1940s (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, Serge Prokofieff, c. 1921 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, Russian, c.1930-1950 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, Mario Sylva (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Manuscripts, English, c.1930-1950 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Manuscripts, Russian, 1940s (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Photographs, Identified, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Photographs, Unidentified, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Clippings, English, c.1940s (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Clippings, Russian, c.1940s (Box 3, Folder 2-3)
- Ephemera, 1920s-1940s (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Scope and Content
  Includes naturalization papers and passports.
- Pocket Diaries and Postcards, 1920s-1940s (Box 4)
- Igor Stravinsky, Clippings, 1940s (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Igor Stravinsky, Correspondence, 1930s-1940s (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Correspondence includes items in English, French and Russian; letters to and from Kall and/or Stravinsky; Stravinsky to Pierre Monteux; Stravinsky on the occasion of the death of Maurice Ravel.
- Igor Stravinsky, Ephemera, 1940s (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Includes an essay by Stan Barnett, "The Neglect of Tchaikovsky's Genius" and 'Ballet of the Winds' by Alice Leal Pollock.
- Igor Stravinsky, List of Works and Overview of Career, c.1940 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Igor Stravinsky, Materials Relating to the Norton Lectures (Charles Eliot Norton Chair of Poetry), Harvard University, 1939-1940 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Igor Stravinsky, Photographs, c.1940s (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Includes cartoon of Stravinsky and photograph of Stravinsky and Edward G. Robinson.
- Igor Stravinsky, Programs of Performances of music written and conducted by Stravinsky, 1939-1940 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Igor Stravinsky, Ralph Berton essay celebrating Stravinsky's achievements, 1935 (Box 5, File 8)